Hello friends welcome to Extra.
Infosys quarter final
result is out here first of all you
can see that Infosys has announced
deferral for its shareholders by sharing the Rupee Pass,
but this is the final decision,
after this the approval of the company's shareholders is
required, which will be obtained in the company's exam
and see here the exam
is going to be held on 25th June and then
here it is written only one, please
see this also it will be on 1st June, this
deferral will give record, that is,
a bed will be on 31st May and if you
want deferral then you have to buy
Infosys shares within 30th, that is, within 30th May,
then you will be
eligible for updates and see here
you will get deferral on 28th June
now let's go directly to the company's
research numbers
hello friends ours are here
above Infosys numbers sometimes you will
see the numbers in crores here first we will
start here with revenue from
operations  It is written very small
but what to do, now this is the company's
side, see here this time
this is the number and this is the previous time means the
number of water three and this is the number of water three of last year is
given here, this time
Infosys' revenue from operations is
32,200.76 which was 26309.11 last year
and in its previous quarter it was 3867 which
you can see here, a good
growth is being seen, friend and share and
environment water also, I will
show you the number by zooming here once so that
you can see it clearly, now if
Infosys' other income is added to it, then
its total income this time will be
32920.13 which was 32 thousand 300.179 in the previous quarter
and its
quarter for last year was 26 thousand 856, so you
can say that the company's income has been very
good, a very good jump from last year to this year.  It
is visible and
this time a slight increase is also being seen from the previous quarter.
Now let us take a
look at the company's expenditure figures here
because that is also very important. It will
not be enough just by having income, it is
important for us to keep the expenses under control.
Look here the total expense is written,
this time the total expense of Infosys is 25
thousand 370 and in the previous quarter it was
24 thousand 436 and in the quarter of the previous year it
was
19931. You can say that the expenses of the company have
increased year after year here and here a
slight increase is also being seen quarter after quarter
but there is no
denying it, but if the expenses increase then the expenses also increase,
you also know this, this is what happens with all of us.
Now look here the profit and tax
means
what is left in the hands of the company after expenses and before paying taxes is
written here which is
7545 and in the previous quarter it was
7946 and towards the end of the previous year it was 1  6900
35 So you can say that year after year we are
seeing a significant jump in profit here,
but quarter after quarter we are
seeing a slight decrease in profit here compared to the previous quarter.
If you want to understand how the company lost its
quarterly profit despite such good income, then
you can see here the list of company's profit.
Here you will have to read it closely,
they say between the
lines. If you compare the profit of this quarter with the previous quarter,
then you will understand that there has been a
little more space in the quarter for water free than the express, the
effect of which has been seen in the profit
promised here this time. Now
look here, the main profit left in the hands of the company after paying taxes is
written here as profit for the prepaid.
I will zoom it a little so that you can
see it clearly. Here
you can see the main profit of Infosys this time, which was 5 thousand
695, which was in the previous quarter.
5826 and last year in the fourth quarter it was
5078. By the way, don't think of these numbers as just thousands;
these are all in crores.
Look here, this is the main problem for Infosys. It is
seeing a good growth,
but if seen quarter-on-quarter, that is,
compared to the previous quarter, there is a
slight decline in profits,
but this will not ruin the company. This will
not make any difference to the company. This is
only the earnings of 3 months
of the company. The company is not in loss. It has made a
profit of 5,695 crores. Now,
look at this, so there is no
need to worry. Infosys' results were good, and the
company is a very good company. If
its numbers increase or decrease in these 12 quarters,
it does not matter. Friends,
if you have this stock in your portfolio, then you
can easily fold it. There is no problem. The
company is a giant in the IT sector and is a
very good company. Now, let's
look at the company's EPS.
Adjust it a little. You can understand that these are very
small numbers. Adding them is very
difficult.  Yes, here it is, the EPS of this company
was 13.86 in the last quarter and
this quarter it is 3.66 point six,
see here last year's quarterly
form was 11.96, here you
can clearly see that this is near, so a good
jump is visible here
but compared to the previous quarter,
you can see a slight decrease here but it does not
matter, you know I have already talked about this some time ago
that if such a good
company loses one or two then it does not make
any difference, so friends, this was
Infosys's quarterly result this time,
according to me, if I say later, the
results were fine, there is no problem, so that is all the
information for now, if you liked it then do
like the video and if you are
new to this channel then subscribe to this channel
because
we keep bringing updates related to the stock market on this channel, so
we will meet
in the next video, till then goodbye